33. The Nazca Lines of Peru. Flying over southern Peru, you may look down to see a
flat red land covered in white sketches of hummingbirds, fish, monkeys, dogs, and plants.
They're simple line drawings, but they're huge. Some of the biggest are nearly 270 meters.
Who made them? Why? Experts believe the huge pictures called Nazca Lines were built by the
Nazca people of ancient Peru. They aren't certain when the lines were made, but they
estimate between 200 B.C. and 8600. The drawings are so huge and beautiful that some people
believe that the ancient Nazca people couldn't have made them. They believe the Nazca lines
are clear signs that aliens or people from more advanced civilizations visited the Nazca
people and helped them. There is no other evidence for this theory. Many other experts and scientists
have experimented using the tools of the Nazca people, and they've shown that the Nazca really
could have made the lines themselves. The lines and drawings must have been hard to organize,
but relatively easy to make. The basic process was to clear away the red stones that covered
the desert to show the white earth below. That's why, from far away, the lines look lighter than
the land. This brings us to another question. Why would the Nazca people build huge figures
that could only be seen from the sky? Perhaps the drawings were for their gods looking down
from the sky. Other theories say that the lines pointed to stars and planets or to sources of
water. However, there is no complete agreement on the purpose of the lines. As with many ancient
monuments, we may never be able to say how or why, but we can still appreciate their beauty and
marvel at the accomplishments of our ancestors.